Register of the Anson Conger Goodyear Papers, 1919-1922
Hoover Institution Archives
Anson Conger Goodyear Papers, 1919-1922
56024
Goodyear, Anson Conger, 1877-1964
3 manuscript boxes, 3 envelopes. (1.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, diary, speeches and writings, memoranda, reports, maps, clippings, printed matter, and photographs, relating to coal production and distribution in Silesia, Bohemia, Galicia, and Serbia, political and economic conditions in Poland, and the partition of Silesia.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Allied and Associated Powers (1914-1920) Supreme Economic Council. Coal Mission (Central Europe); Inter-Allied Commission in Upper Silesia.; Coal mines and mining--Bohemia (Czechoslovakia); Coal mines and mining--Galicia (Poland and Ukraine); Coal mines and mining--Serbia.; Coal mines and mining--Silesia (Germany); Reconstruction (1914-1939); Bohemia (Czechoslovakia); Czechoslovakia.; Galicia (Poland and Ukraine); Germany.; Poland.; Poland--History--1918-1945.; Serbia.; Silesia (Germany)--Economic conditions.; Silesia (Poland: Voivodeship)--Economic conditions.; Yugoslavia.
Biographical Note
1877, June 20 Born, Buffalo, New York
1899 Bachelor Degree, Yale University
1900-1911 Chairman of the Executive Committee, Director, G.M. & O. Railroads Director, Crown Zellerbach Corporation President, Goodyear Lumber Company
1911-1917 President, Norwich Lumber Company
1917 Captain, Field Artillery, U.S. Army
1918 Colonel; Commander, 307th Field Artillery
1918 Commander, 81st Field Artillery, France
1918 General Inspector, Transportation Corps, A.E.F.
1918, May 2 President, Coal Commission for Central Europe
1919, September 5 Member, Inter-Allied Commission on Upper Silesia
1919, October Discharged honorably from the two last posts
1919 Major General, 1st Division, New York National Guard
1929-1960 Trustee, President, Museum of Modern Art, New York
1944-1945 Deputy Commander, American Red Cross, Pacific Ocean Areas
1947 Personal Representative of Secretary of War, American Zone, Germany and Austria
1952 Master of Laws, Norwich University
1958 Doctor of Fine Arts, Adelphi College
1964, April 23 Died, Old Westbury, New York
Series Description
- COAL COMMISSION FILE, 1919. (Box Boxes 1-2)
  Reports, resolutions, agreements, lists, protocols, newsclippings, press releases, press translations, maps and other documents produced by the Coal Commission, arranged by physical form
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1920-1922. (Box 2)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
- DIARY, 1919. (Box 2)
  Goodyear's daily activities between August 21, 1919 and September 23, 1919
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1919-1920. (Box 2)
  Memoirs on political, social and economic conditions in Central Europe, and speeches delivered after Goodyear's return to the United States
- MISCELLANY, 1919. (Box 2)
  Calling cards, invitations, railway tickets, ID card, report, leaflet, materials connected with Goodyear's stay in Central Europe
- INTER-ALLIED COMMISSION OFFICE FILE, 1919. (Box 3)
  Reports, correspondence, memoranda, newsclippings, leaflets, arranged by physical form
- PHOTOGRAPHS. (File Photo file)
  See photo card catalog
Container List
- COAL COMMISSION FILE, 1919
  - Founding documents, appointments, goals of the Commission (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - List of the Commission members and their duties (Folder 2)
  - Chronological list of conferences held by Colonel Goodyear between May 4, 1919 and July 17, 1919 (Folder 3)
  - Protocols, resolutions, agreements, appeals (Folder 4)
  - Newsclippings, press releases, press notes, translations (Folder 5)
  - Memoranda
    - Memorandum for Major Brand. Current Coal Supplies and the Directives for Further Actions in the Countries Involved: Czechoslovakia, Germany, Poland, Austria (Folder 6)
    - Memoranda for Captain Watterson Goodyear's description of his trips, their purposes and accomplishments; recommendations for the conduct of the commission's office (Folder 7)
  - Reports on the Commission's activities (in five chapters), written by Goodyear for his successor and describing Headquarters, personnel, political reality in Central Europe, reporting on negotiations, conferences and contracts (Folder 8)
  - Reports relating to economic policy
    - Report on Coal Mines in Ostrau-Karwin District, June 1919 (Folder 9)
    - Report on Coal Production and Food Requirements in Ostrau-Karwin District and Contiguous District, June 1919 (Folder 10)
    - Report on Coal Mines in Upper Silesia, Bohemia, Serbia, June-July 1919 (Folder 11)
    - Reports on Coal Mines in Hungary and Dumbrowa, Poland and Oil and Gas Fields in Galicia, June-August 1919 (Folder 12)
    - Report on the Coal Fields of Czechoslovakia, July 1919 (Folder 13)
    - Reports on Coal Mines in Galicia, July 1919 (Folder 14)
    - Reports on Coal Mines in German Austria and Trafail District, August 1919 (Folder 15)
    - Report of the Coal Commission for the Territory Included in the Former Empire of Austria-Hungary and Poland, September 1919 (Folder 16)
    - Memorandum. The Economic Future of Upper Silesia, January 1922 (Folder 17)
    - Distribution of Coal within the Territory of the Old Empire, n.d. (Folder 18)
  - Correspondence
    - Allied Railway Mission to Poland (Folder 19)
    - American Relief Administration (Folder 20)
    - Czechoslovak government agencies (Folder 21)
    - German government agencies (Folder 22)
    - Ministry of Reconstruction, Belgrade, Kingdom of Serbia, Croatia and Slovenia (Folder 23)
    - Ministry of Trade and Industry, Warsaw, Poland (Folder 24)
    - Correspondence concluding Coal Commission activities (Folder 25)
  - Maps (Box 2)
    - Administrativ-Karte der Erzherz. Kammer Teschen in Oesterr. Schlesien (Folder 1)
    - Central Europe - Major coal mines (Folder 2)
    - Central Europe - Regions of pit coal and lignites (Folder 3)
    - European Coal Production and Distribution in 1913. (Folder 4)
    - General Industriekarte vom Oberschlesischen Rusischen und Maehrisch-Ostrauer Revier (Folder 5)
    - Handkarte des Oberschlesischen Industriebezirks (Folder 6)
    - Uebersichtskarte des Oberschlesischen Industriebezirkes, (7 charts) (Folder 7)
    - Uebersichtskarte des Ostrau-Karwiner Steinkohlrevieres, (6 charts) (Folder 8)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1920-1922
  - Barber, A.B., Technical Adviser to the Ministry of Railways, Warsaw, Poland, 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Causey, W.B., Colonel, Technical Adviser to Austria, 1921-1922 (Folder 10)
  - Stader, J.A., Captain, Coal Commission member, 1920-1921 (Folder 11)
  - General correspondence, 1920 (Folder 12)
- DIARY, 1919.
  - Goodyear's diary of his daily activities, between August 21 and September 23, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, ca. 1919-1920
  - Memoirs. Goodyear's memoir on his involvement in Coal Commission and Inter-Allied Commission, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Peace in Eastern Europe", n.d. (Folder 15)
  - Untitled writing related to insurrection in Upper Silesia, n.d. (Folder 16)
  - Untitled speech to University Club on political developments in Central Europe, November 29, 1919 (Folder 17)
- MISCELLANY, 1919
  - Calling cards, invitations, railway tickets, ID card (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Printed matter
    - Brochure, Report of European Technical Adviser's Mission to Poland, 1919-1922, by A.B. Barber, New York, 1923 (Folder 19)
    - Leaflet. An Open Letter to the English and the American Nation, by the Committee for National Defense of Poland, Lwow, June 1919 (Folder 20)
    - Schoolbooks (Folder 21)
      - Nova Brana Jazyku. Bilingual reader in Czech and English, Holesou, 1916
      - Puopata, Czech elementary, Prag, 1914
      - Anglicky, Snadno a Rychle, Handbook on English, Prag, n.d.
- INTER-ALLIED COMMISSION FILE, 1919-1920
  - Alleged German official documents inciting revolt (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - German and Polish complaints (Folder 2)
  - German official papers (Folder 3)
  - Letters to Herbert Hoover and Hugh Gibson (Folder 4)
  - Memoranda of conferences (Folder 5)
  - Press comments (Folder 6)
  - Report of Colonel Goodyear on Upper Silesian Insurrection (Folder 7)
  - Reports of Inter-Allied Commission for Upper Silesia (Folder 8)
  - Subject file
    - Polish - Czechoslovak border conflict (Folder 9)
    - Political origins of Inter-Allied Commission (Folder 10)
    - Release of hostages (Folder 11)
    - Upper Silesia
      - Miscellaneous papers (Folder 12)
      - Pamphlets, newspapers, maps (Folder 13)
      - Telegrams (Folder 14)
- PHOTOGRAPHS.
  - See photo card catalog. (File Photo file)